<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" href="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/code/pfs.css"?><TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>A dreadful account of the horrid murther of Mr. Tilly and the narrow escape of his wife, at the Boors-Head in Lambeth, on Monday the 14th. of May, 1694.</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 4KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 1 1-bit group-IV TIFF page image.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2016-02">2016-02 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">B21351</idno><idno type="EEBO-CITATION">99827264</idno>
  <idno type="VID">206840</idno>
  <idno type="EEBO-PROQUEST">2248498403</idno>
  
            <idno type="STC">Wing D2149</idno>
            <idno type="PROQUEST">99827264</idno>
            <availability><p>This keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above is co-owned by the
    institutions providing financial support to the Early English Books Online Text Creation
    Partnership. This text is available for reuse, according to the terms of <ref target="https://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/"> Creative Commons 0 1.0 Universal
    licence</ref>. The text can be copied, modified, distributed and performed, even for commercial
    purposes, all without asking permission.</p></availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online text creation partnership.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt><relatedItem type="facs" target="https://data.historicaltexts.jisc.ac.uk/view?pubId=eebo-99827264e"/>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. B21351)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 206840)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English books, 1641-1700 ; 1846:21)</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>A dreadful account of the horrid murther of Mr. Tilly and the narrow escape of his wife, at the Boors-Head in Lambeth, on Monday the 14th. of May, 1694.</title>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>1 sheet ([1] p.)   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>printed, and are to be sold by Randal Taylor near Stationers-Hall,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>London :</pubPlace>
                  <date>1694.</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>At end of title: Lisenc'd, May 16th. 1694.</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of the original in the Bodleian Library.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,363 texts created during Phase 1 of the project have been released into the public domain as of 1 January 2015. Anyone can now take and use these texts for their own purposes, but we respectfully request that due credit and attribution is given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Full documentation of the original data capture process is available from the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.
   All versions of the texts are now archived and freely available for download. See <ref target="https://textcreationpartnership.org/faq/#faq05">the TCP Download FAQ</ref>
   for detailed information. The TEI P5 versions are also freely available from the <ref target="https://github.com/textcreationpartnership">TCP Github repository</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp" matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)" replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term type="personal_name">Tilly, --  Mr., d. 1694 --  Early works to 1800.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2014-03 </date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images </change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-05 </date>
            <label>Anne Simpson </label>Sampled and proofread </change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-05 </date>
            <label>Anne Simpson</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited </change>
         <change>
            <date>2015-03 </date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion </change>
      <change><date>2021-05 </date><label>lb</label>TEI P5 conversion </change></revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <body>
         <div type="text">
            <pb facs="tcp:206840:1"/>
            <head>Dreadful Account OF THE <hi>Horrid Murther of Mr. Tilly,</hi> And the Narrow Escape of his Wife, at the <hi>Boors-Head</hi> in <hi>LAMBETH,</hi> on <hi>Monday</hi> the 14th of <hi>May,</hi> 1694.</head>
            <q>
               <floatingText xml:lang="eng">
                  <body>
                     <div type="license">
                        <p>Lisenc'd, <hi>May</hi> 16th. 1694.</p>
                     </div>
                  </body>
               </floatingText>
            </q>
            <q>
               <p>
                  <hi>Murther</hi> and <hi>Theft</hi> have been always lookt upon as most detestable Sins in the Sight of God and Man, and punish'd as Capital Offences. The Commands of God, the Laws of the Jews, and other Nations at this day, inflict Death on the miserable Criminal.</p>
               <p>If our Body is the Temple of God, let us keep it undefiled, and not Make it a Sanctuary for <hi>Murther</hi> and <hi>Theft;</hi> for that Holy Spirit will not endure the Impurity of our Thoughts, much less our polluted Actions: Our hands must not only be free from the stain of Blood, but our Hearts from the guilt, and the very desire of Revenge. He that sheds his Brothers Blood, stains his own Soul, which nothing can wash away, but that <hi>Fountain of Living Water,</hi> which cleanseth from all unrighteousness. The Judg<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ments of Heaven may seem to follow the Impenitent Sinner with Leaden Feet, yet they strike at last with Hands of Iron.</p>
            </q>
            <div type="account">
               <head>The Account is as follows, <hi>viz.</hi>
               </head>
               <p>THat between 9 and 10 of the Clock at night, there came three Men into the House of the aforesaid Mr. <hi>Tilly,</hi> enquiring for a Boat-Builder at the next door; but he happening to be abroad, his Wife came: They asking, <hi>Where her Hus<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>band was?</hi> She replyed, <hi>He was abroad, but cou'd not tell where.</hi> They enquir'd further, <hi>Whether she had ever an Old Boat to sell?</hi> She reply'd, <hi>She had none at this time;</hi> and went her way from them. No Company being in the house but an old Soldier, Mr. <hi>Tilly</hi> told him, <hi>He would not stay with him, but go to keep the Gentlemen Company.</hi> The Gentlemen reply'd, <hi>Do so old Father,</hi> and so drunk to him.</p>
               <p>Soon after, the Soldier went to Bed, so that no body was left below but Mr. <hi>Tilly</hi> and his Wife, and these Gentlemen.</p>
               <p>Soon after, these persons call'd for Mr. <hi>Tilly's</hi> Wife to fetch more Drink; and in her going down the Cellar-stairs, one of these Men pursu'd her, and knock'd her down; but that would not satisfy his Cruelty, but ty'd her in the Cellar, and stopt her Mouth with a Handkerchief; while the others above-stairs barbarously Assaulted Mr. <hi>Tilly</hi> himself, who the next Morning about 4 of the Clock was found dead, and ty'd in the Chimney-corner. The Wife was found in the Cellar, very near Death, and continu'd so for about 5 or 6 Hours before she began to recover. And now (blessed be God) she is capable of giving satisfaction of this most Dismal and Tra<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gical Account, to all such Persons as desire to be further satisfy'd.</p>
               <p>These most Inhumane and Barbarous Persons, when they thought all safe and secure from mollestation, they took the opportunity to rifle the House of Mony, and carry'd off an Iron-bound Chest, and other things of great Value. And when they thought they had done what mischief they could, they took a Boat to go by water, which was found next Morning at <hi>Blackfryers-stairs.</hi> — None of the persons are taken as yet.</p>
            </div>
         </div>
      </body>
      <back>
         <div type="colophon">
            <p>
               <hi>London</hi> Printed, and are to be sold by <hi>Randal Taylor</hi> near <hi>Stationers-Hall,</hi> 1694.</p>
         </div>
      </back>
   </text>
</TEI>